<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<component>
  <id>de.linrunner.tlp</id>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <name>TLP</name>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0-or-later AND GPL-3.0</project_license>
  <summary>Optimize laptop battery life</summary>
  <url type="homepage">https://linrunner.de/tlp</url>
  <developer id="de.linrunner">
     <name>Thomas Koch</name>
  </developer>

  <description>
    <p>
        TLP is a feature-rich command-line utility, saving laptop battery power
        without the need to delve deeper into technical details.
    </p>
    <p>
        TLP’s default settings are already optimized for battery life and implement
        Powertop’s recommendations out of the box. Moreover TLP is highly
        customizable to fulfil specific user requirements.
    </p>
    <p>
        Settings are organized into the three customizable profiles performance (AC),
        balanced (BAT) and power-saver (SAV), allowing to adjust between savings
        and performance independently for battery and AC operation.
    </p>
    <p>
        The optional TLP Profiles Daemon (tlp-pd) implements the D-Bus interface,
        which lets desktop environments show a power profile switch.
        Together with TLP as the backend for applying the customizable profiles,
        it replaces power-profiles-daemon.
    </p>
    <p>
        In addition TLP can enable or disable Bluetooth, NFC, Wi-Fi and WWAN
        devices at boot time, as well as automated switching when a LAN cable is
        connected or removed, or when the laptop is docked or undocked.
    </p>
    <p>
        For ThinkPads and may other laptop brands it provides a unified way
        to configure charge thresholds and recalibrate the battery.
    </p>
  </description>

  <categories>
    <category>System</category>
  </categories>

  <!-- Do we want software centers to automatically launch TLP ? -->
  <!-- <launchable type="service">tlp</launchable> -->
  <provides>
    <!-- Match "Portable" chassis type -->
    <modalias>dmi:*:ct8:*</modalias>
    <!-- Match "Laptop" chassis type -->
    <modalias>dmi:*:ct9:*</modalias>
    <!-- Match "Notebook" chassis type -->
    <modalias>dmi:*:ct10:*</modalias>
    <!-- Match "battery" kernel module -->
    <modalias>acpi:PNP0C0A:*</modalias>
  </provides>
</component>
